（环球出口有限公司 伦敦）
我多年来一直都说 我们的特别仪器过时了
I've said for years that our special equipment is obsolete.
现在借着电脑分析显示 仪器有微型化的趋势
And now, computer analysis reveals a new approach: miniaturization.
比如说 放射性线头
For instance, radioactive lint.
放进敌人的口袋里
When placed in an opponent's pockets…
就可以找到对方的位置
…the personnel and location fix seems obvious.
我们要找的是007的位置
What we want is a location fix on 007.
十号情报员为了“疯人院行动” 大发牢骚
Number 10 is making ugly noises about Operation Bedlam.
钱班霓 跟通讯部门联络了没？
Miss Moneypenny, did you check with Communications?
开罗 阿姆斯特丹和穆德里 都没有他的消息
Replies to our Cairo, Amsterdam and Madrid inquiries: all negative.
若找到007 首相希望我们私下通知他
The PM wants to be informed personally when we find 007.
我叫邦德 詹姆斯邦德 你是…
Good morning. My name's Bond. James Bond. Miss…
别动 邦德先生
Don't move, Mr. Bond.
现在站起来
Now get up!
把双手放在脑后
Put your hands behind your head.
走吧
Move!
进去
Get in.
躺下来
Lie down.
其他人就不会遇上这种事
This never happened to the other fellow.
《007系列之女王密使》
- 有行李吗？- 在行李箱
- Baggage, sir? - In the boot.
- 小心那些球杆 - 没问题
- Take care of those clubs. - Right, sir.
- 邦德长官 你好吗？- 曼努尔 好高兴见到你
- Commander Bond. How are you? - Good to see you, Manuel.
看来保持着一贯的高水平
Everything seems up to the Palacio's usual standards.
对 这个季节的生意不错
Yes, it's a good season.
那红色车子的主人 是一位女士吗？
That red car, does it belong to a lady?
对 是泰丽莎文西佐伯爵夫人
Yes. Contessa Teresa di Vincenzo.
这是最上等的房间
Our best.
幸好客人临时取消订房
Fortunately, we have had a cancellation.
跟我来
Allow me.
行了 这就好了
This will do. This will do me nicely.
我们一定能照顾你特别的需要
I'm sure we can look after your special needs.
是的 谢谢你
I'm sure you can. Thank you.
（赌场）
谢谢
Thank you.
两万法郎
Twenty thousand francs.
对我来说太多了
Too rich for my blood.
小姐？
Madame?
我没钱
I don't have the money.
抱歉 但是我没钱
I regret too, but I don't have any money.
她付不出钱
The dame can't pay up.
抱歉 我没有集中精神
Forgive me. My mind was elsewhere.
她忘了今晚我们是拍档
Madame has forgotten we agreed to be partners this evening.
请继续
Please continue.
真幸运 最后关头有人解围
That's lucky, being bailed out like that at the last minute.
服务生
Waiter.
- 一九五七年的当培利洋香槟 - 是的
- Dom Perignon, '57. - Yes, sir.
你干嘛老是要救我？
Why do you persist in rescuing me, Mr. Bond?
这成为我的习惯 泰丽莎伯爵夫人
It's becoming a habit, Contessa Teresa.
泰丽莎是个圣人 叫我崔西
Teresa was a saint. I'm known as Tracy.
崔西 下次不要冒险
Tracy, next time play it safe and stand on five.
不想死的人才不敢冒险
People who want to stay alive play it safe.
请好好的活着 至少今晚不要死
Please stay alive, at least for tonight.
待会儿上来
Come later.
希望真的值得吧拍档
I hope it'll be worth it, partner.
送到423号套房 加两份鱼子酱
Send it to suite 423 with caviar for two.
崔西？
Tracy?
冲锋客
Gatecrasher.
你来清理这儿吧
I'll leave you to tidy up.
是皇室白鲟 来自里海北部
Royal beluga, north of the Caspian.
- 伯爵夫人 你总是叫人意外 - 你也是
- You're full of surprises, contessa. - So are you, Mr. Bond.
你约会时都带着手枪的吗？
Do you always have a gun for a rendezvous?
有时候吧 我是个易出事的人
Occasionally. I seem to be accident-prone.
你不介意的话 把枪给我
I'll take that, if you don't mind.
你挺有自信
You're very confident.
若我为了好玩而杀了你呢？
Suppose I kill you for a thrill?
有其他方法可以增进彼此了解
I can think of something more sociable to do.
别再玩了 你房里的男人是谁？
Stop playing games. Who was that man in your room?
- 你弄得我好痛 - 我以为这是今晚的目的
- You're hurting me. - I thought that was the idea tonight.
快说 他是谁？
Now, who was he?
我不明白你说什么？
I don't know what you're talking about.
我可以更有说服力
I can be a lot more persuasive.
我知道你可以
I'm sure you can.
不管我是谁 我不是骗子
Whatever else I may be, I'm not a liar.
穿上衣服
Get dressed.
你是个很特别的女孩
You're the most extraordinary girl.
我对你的评语没兴趣
I'm not interested in your opinion of me, Mr. Bond.
- 我来这儿为了做生意 - 真的吗？
- I'm here for a business transaction. - Really?
蓝这种牌子太浓了吧？
Isn't Le Bleu a bit heady for that?
除了香水以外 你还懂得什么？
You know your perfumes. What else do you know?
我了解一点女人
A little about women.
就当我是
Think about me…
你刚买回来的女人
…as a woman you've just bought.
我怎么需要买女人？
Who needs to buy?
你没欠我什么
Look, you don't owe me a thing.
我觉得你好像有麻烦
I think you're in trouble.
想跟我谈一谈吗？
Would you like to talk about it?
不想 邦德先生
No, Mr. Bond.
你只需要知道 我会还欠你的钱
The only thing you need know about me is that I pay my debts.
两万法郎不是小数目
Twenty thousand francs is a lot of money.
- 早 邦德长官 - 咖啡室订座 两位
- Good morning, Commander Bond. - Good morning. Cafe complet for two.
- 是的 长官 - 替我接423房
- Yes, sir. - Connect me with suite 423, please.
文西佐伯爵夫人已经退房了
The Contessa di Vincenzo has left the hotel, sir.
- 退房了？- 几分钟以前退的
- Checked out? - A few minutes ago.
谢谢
Thank you.
全数归还
Paid in full, as well.
- 邦德先生？- 是的
- Mr. Bond? - Yes.
- 你掉了一些东西 - 真的吗？
- You've lost something. - Really?
我们到外面还给你
We'll give it to you outside.
为何不可？凑够四个人打牌
Why not? Perhaps we can make up a foursome.
你想的真周到
You've thought of everything.
好一个惊喜 那么快又见面了
What a lovely surprise, our meeting again so soon.
这次到哪里玩？
Where's the party this time?
- 你有个约会 - 谈生意还是寻开心？
- You have an appointment. - Business or pleasure?
神秘之旅吧？
Mystery tour, eh?
若你不拿着它 气氛会轻松点
I think we'd enjoy it more without that.
不要杀我 邦德先生
Do not kill me, Mr. Bond.
起码先让我们喝点酒
At least not until we've had a drink.
若你还是要杀我 我再给你机会吧
Then if you wish, I'll give you another chance.
我是跩哥 跩哥建筑公司的老板
I'm Draco, of Draco Construction.
- 今天是十三号 先生 - 我很迷信
- But today is the 13th, commander. - I'm superstitious.
- 给客人一杯马丁尼 - 好的
- A martini for our guest. - A pleasure.
要摇的 不要搅的
Shaken, not stirred.
- 当然 - 给我一杯堪培利酒
- Of course. - Campari for me.
很对不起用这种方式把你带来 请坐
My apologies for the way you were brought here today. Please sit down.
我不肯定你会否接受正式的邀请
I was not sure you would accept a formal invitation.
要动用手枪 一定是正式的事情
There's always something formal about the point of a pistol.
谢谢 甜心
Thank you, cheri.
我们待会儿再继续挣扎吧
Olympe, we will finish our struggle later.
好的
As you wish.
她下西洋棋很棒的
And she also plays a very good game of chess.
干杯
Cheers.
你常常喝科西嘉白兰地
You usually drink Corsican brandy.
你还知道我什么事情？
What else do you know about me?
马克安跩哥 科西嘉联盟首脑
Marc Ange Draco: Head of the Union Corse.
那是欧洲庞大的犯罪集团
A big crime syndicate in Europe.
- 最大的犯罪集团 - 也不算
- The biggest. - Not quite.
还有一个叫幽灵的国际性集团
An organization known as SPECTRE operates worldwide.
但你的合法生意比较广泛
But your legitimate business fronts are more extensive.
建筑 电子产品
Construction, electrical supplies…
还有无数的农业公司
…numerous agricuItural holdings.
你手上关于我的档案
Your dossier on me…
不够完整
…is not entirely complete.
我也是泰丽莎的爸爸
I am also Teresa's father.
- 崔西 - 是的
- Tracy. - Yes, Tracy.
她是我唯一的孩子
Tracy. My only child.
她的母亲是英国人
Her mother was an English girl.
她很浪漫 她到科西嘉寻找强盗
A romantic who had come to Corsica to look for bandits.
就像那些到沙漠 寻找酋长的女人一样
Rather like those women who ventured into the desert looking for sheiks.
她在山上找到我
She found me in the mountains…
当时我正在逃避警方追捕
…hiding from the police at the time.
后来我就爱上她
I came to love this girl.
我们结婚了 结果生下了泰丽莎
We married. The resuIt: Teresa.
十二年后 我太太死了 我送泰丽莎到瑞士去
Twelve years later, my wife died. I sent Teresa to Switzerland…
- 不 谢谢 我喜欢自己的 - 送她去完成学业
- No, thanks, I prefer my own. - …to finish her education.
可惜我没有给她一个温暖的家
Unfortunately, I didn't give her a proper home.
没有人看管她
She was without supervision.
所以她跟一伙坏人混上了
So she joined a fast international set.
搞出一桩又一桩丑事
One scandal after another.
我不满意的时候 就不给她生活费
When I disapproved, cut off her allowance…
她就更放纵
…she committed some greater folly…
故意要令我烦恼
…to spite me.
然而 在她虚张声势的外表下
And yet, behind her bravado…
内心却十分空虚
…something was eating away at her soul.
这情况都可能发生在 所有人的身上
This can happen to men and women.
他们太贪婪 伤害自己的心
They burn the heart out of themselves by living too greedily…
突然之间
…and suddenly…
- 一切都完了 - 干嘛告诉我这些？
- …all is finished. - Why tell me this?
她嫁给
She married…
一个意大利伯爵
…an Italian count who killed himself…
那家伙跟他其中一个情妇 死在一辆法拉利内
…in a Maserati with one of his mistresses.
我给她的太多 结果却一无所有
I gave her too much, and it brought her nothing.
我干嘛告诉你这些
Now, why I tell you all this.
我知道你为我的女儿所做的一切
I've been informed of everything you've done for my daughter.
- 一切？- 别担心
- Everything? - Don't worry. Don't worry about that.
你所做的 你的表现
What you did, the way you behaved…
可能是对她的治疗的开始
…might be the beginning of some kind of therapy.
她需要帮助
She needs help.
你的帮助
Your help.
我觉得她不错 但她需要的是 精神病医生 不是我
I find her fascinating, but she needs a psychiatrist, not me.
她需要一个能支配她的男人
What she needs is a man to dominate her…
跟她上床 直到让她爱上他
…to make love to her enough to make her love him.
你正是合适人选
A man like you.
你高估我了
You overestimate me, Draco.
她很吸引 但你要找的人不是我
She's very attractive, but what you ask is not for me.
听着 你跟她结婚那天
Listen to me. On the day you marry her…
我会私下给你嫁妆 是价值一百万磅的
…I'll give you a personal dowry of one million pounds…
黄金
…in gold.
条件很吸引人
That's quite an inducement.
但我不需要一百万磅黄金
But I don't need a million pounds.
而且我喜欢自由
And I have a taste for freedom.
请你多跟她在一起 谁知道结果会怎么样？
Please, just see her some more. Who knows what will come of it?
对不起 碍于我的工作 我不能
I'm sorry, Draco, but in my profession, I can't…
- 什么？- 你还有事情隐瞒我
- What? - You have connections not open to me.
欧士斯达洛布费德在哪里？
Where is Ernst Stavro Blofeld?
布费德？
Blofeld?
我的几个部下跟他走了 我不知道他在哪里
Some of my men defected to him. I don't know where he is.
- 能够找到他吗？- 即使我知道
- Can you find out? - If I could…
也不会告诉特工处
…I wouldn't tell Her Majesty's Secret Service…
我只会告诉我未来的女婿
…but I might tell my future son-in-law.
继续吧
Go on.
下星期是我的生日
Next week is my birthday.
泰丽莎通常会回来贺寿
For that, Teresa always comes back to me.
你明白吗？
You understand?
- 我会考虑你的建议 - 很好
- Let's say I'll sleep on the idea. - You do that.
詹姆斯 你去了哪儿？
James, where have you been?
- 离你很远的地方 甜心 - 还是老样子
- Much too far from you, darling. - Same old James.
而且变本加厉
Only more so.
没心肝的好色鬼 让我消瘦 连明信片也没有
Heartless brute, letting me pine away without even a postcard.
不用再消瘦了
Pine no more.
到我家喝鸡尾酒吧 八点钟 只我们两个
Cocktails at my place, 8-ish, just the two of us.
感谢你的邀请
Oh, I'd adore that…
但我可不相信自己
…if only I could trust myself.
还是老样子 活像英国的最后防线
Same old Moneypenny: Britain's last line of defense.
你最好快点进去 他今天很忙碌
You'd better go in. He's running a very tight ship today.
我要终止你的疯人院行动
I'm relieving you from Operation Bedlam, 007.
但我必须对付布费德
But, sir, Blofeld's something of a must with me.
你找他找了两年了
You've had two years to run him down.
你对我失去信心了？
You've lost confidence in me?
我很清楚你的才干
I'm well aware of your talents, 007…
但杀人通行证也要找到他才管用
…but license to kill is useless unless one has a target.
我会给你另一个更合适的任务 就这样
I'll find you a more suitable assignment. That's all.
- 长官 - 就这样
- Sir… - That's all.
会议那么快就结束
That was a quick conference.
你怎么要一个女孩保持吸引力
How do you expect a girl to keep herself alluring?
给我写一张备忘录
Take a memo, please.
- 准备好了 - 我郑重请求
- Ready, James. - Sir, I have the honor to request…
你接受我的辞职 即时生效
…you will accept my resignation, effective forthwith.
- 辞什么职？- 辞退英国特工处的工作
- Resignation from what? - Her Majesty's Secret Service.
请把它呈给里面的老顽固
And kindly present it to that monument in there.
对不起
Sorry, ma'am.
我是詹姆斯邦德
007… James Bond here.
他要见你
He wants you, James.
请求获准了
Request granted.
请求获准了 连挽留都没有
Request granted. Not even with regret.
你想怎么了 想当爵士吗？
What did you expect, a knighthood?
干嘛不看看它
Why don't you read it?
两星期假期
"Two weeks leave."
你不是真的想辞职吧？
You didn't really want to resign, did you?
钱班霓 没有你我怎么办呢？
Moneypenny, what would I do without you?
问题是你从来没有 跟我干过什么
My problem is that you never do anything with me.
等我回来的时候 我跟你约会
It's a date. The moment I get back.
- 你要去哪里？- 找个地方混日子
- Where are you off to? - Just someplace to laze about.
去海边流浪
Beachcombing.
钱班霓 没有你我怎么办？谢谢你
What would I do without you, Miss Moneypenny? Thank you.
你早 米格尔
Bonjour, Miguel.
- 泰丽莎 你好 - 你早
- Teresa, hello. - Good morning.
- 好久不见了 - 你好吗？
- It's so nice that we see you. - How are you?
- 是的 非常好 - 崔西来了
- Yes, very well. - There's Tracy.
她在哪里？在那边
Where is she? Ah, there she is!
- 泰丽莎 - 爸爸生日快乐
- Teresa! - Happy birthday, Papa.
你来了我的生日就快乐 你好漂亮
You make it so by being here. You look marvelous.
我给你介绍一个人 来吧
There's someone I want you to meet. Come.
- 奥莉 你好吗？- 你回来了真好
- Olympe, how are you? - It's good to have you back.
- 你好漂亮 - 谢谢
- You look wonderful. - Thanks.
邦德先生 这是我的女儿泰丽莎
Mr. Bond, may I introduce my daughter, Teresa?
- 伯爵夫人 - 我们见过了
- Contessa. - Mr. Bond and I have already met.
每一次见面都更快乐
Each time is a renewed pleasure.
小姐总让人觉得愉快
Madame always makes one feel so welcome.
她喜欢你 我看得出来
She likes you. I can see it.
介绍你的眼科医生给我吧
You must give me the name of your oculist.
奥莉 我不知道 邦德先生认识爸爸
Olympe, I didn't know Mr. Bond knew Papa.
邦德先生总是让人摸不着头脑
There is much about Mr. Bond one does not know.
也许上夜间部课程会很有趣
It would be interesting to attend night school, perhaps.
爸爸一定在搞些什么
Papa is up to something. I'm sure of it.
他很爱你的 崔西
Your father loves you very much, Tracy.
无论他安排了什么 他只想你高兴
Whatever he may arrange, I know it's for your happiness.
他安排了什么？
What has Papa arranged?
- 邦德先生 - 谢谢
- Ah, Mr. Bond! - Thank you.
- 谢谢 - 祝你越来越快乐
- Thank you. - Many happy returns.
但愿以后越来越好
The best years are still to come, let's hope.
跟我来
Allow me.
你来干嘛？
What are you doing here?
是你爸请我来的 很棒吧？
Yes, wasn't it kind of your father to invite me?
我们在谈生意
We're discussing a business deal.
真的吗？
Really?
女人不会浪费了这好酒 来谈生意
No woman would waste this excellent champagne discussing business.
除非是受到别人的安排吧
Unless she happened to be part of the arrangement.
你对她说了什么？
What did you say?
别骂奥莉了 我最了解你
Don't blame Olympe. I'm not your daughter for nothing.
你们真的很像一家人
I detect a certain family resemblance.
我建议你 重新考虑你们合约的条款
I suggest you revise the terms of your contract, Mr. Bond.
- 你的责任太昂贵了 - 你误会了
- Your liability is too expensive. - There you're mistaken.
- 爸爸 - 怎么了？
- Papa. - Yes?
- 邦德先生想要一些情报 - 你在说什么？
- Mr. Bond wants some information. - What are you talking about?
你教我做一个好主人 要给他客人所需的一切
You taught me that a good host supplies his guests' needs.
而且不需他负责任
And without obligation.
- 那又如何？- 你说负责任不太对
- And then? - "Obligation" is not the right word.
告诉他吧 告诉他希望知道的情报
Tell him, Papa. Tell him what he wants to know.
- 现在就说 - 别这样子
- Now! - Please, Teresa.
只是一个可能 事情没有绝对的
There's only a possibility. Nothing definite.
告诉他 否则你以后不会再见到我
Tell him, Papa, or you'll never see me again.
好的
All right.
那个布费德也许跟
There may be a connection between that man Blofeld…
在瑞士伯尔尼一家公司 的律师有关系
…and a lawyer with offices in Bern, Switzerland.
- 他叫格布德 - 格布德
- Named Gumbold. - Gumbold.
- 瑞士伯尼尔 - 对 格布德
- Bern, Switzerland. - Yes, Gumbold.
那
So…
- 邦德先生不用对我有兴趣 - 你又误会了
- Mr. Bond need have no interest in me. - Another mistake.
她总是那么顽固
She always was a headstrong child.
对不起
I'm sorry…
他去哪里了？
Where has he gone?
崔西
Tracy!
Tracy.
我总觉得要解释误会
I was always taught that mistakes should be remedied.
特别是朋友之间的误会
Especially between friends.
或者情人之间的
Or lovers.
我待会儿去找你
I'll catch up with you later.
- 一如以往？- 记得冰镇我的马丁尼
- The story of our life, James? - Just keep my martini cool.
（戈布达格布德办事处）
我一小时内回来
I will be back in an hour.
这些事情该留给爸爸办 我知道什么对你最好
Such things should be left to a girl's father, who knows best.
有什么事情比谈恋爱更好？
But what could be better than being in love?
邦德先生爱上了你？
Mr. Bond is in love with you?
终有一天
That may come too…
他会爱上我
…someday.
有生之年可能等不到这一天
Life's too short for "someday", Teresa.
明天我会跟他单独谈一谈
Tomorrow I will speak to him alone, man-to-man.
- 不 不要谈 - 为什么？
- No, Papa. No talk. - Why not?
无论如何我也不后悔
Whatever happens, there'll be no regrets.
求求你
Please.
- 午安 - 午安 海军上将在吗？
- Good afternoon. - Good afternoon. Is the admiral in?
不好意思 邦德长官想见你
Excuse me, sir. Commander Bond to see you.
请他进来
Show him in.
- 请你进来 - 谢谢
- Aye, aye, sir. If you please. - Thank you.
它比一般的绿蛱蝶小
Unusually small for a Nymphalis polychloros.
我不知道原来 你对鳞翅目昆虫也有研究
I wasn't aware that your expertise included lepidoptery.
- 你来干嘛？你在放假 - 宗谱学
- Why are you here? You're on leave. - Genealogy.
很有趣
Fascinating subject.
我在瑞士 戈布达格布德律师那里
Found a letter from Gebruder Gumbold, solicitors in Switzerland…
找到给巴达哈博堪普伯爵的信
…to a certain Count BaIthazar de Bleuchamp.
- 博堪普伯爵？- 是法语“布费德”的意思
- De Bleuchamp? - French form of Blofeld.
还记得 你的疯人院行动终止了吗？
You've been relieved from Operation Bedlam, remember?
相信你会重新要我执行行动
I assumed you'd reassign me, sir.
这是信件的副本
This is a Photostat copy of a letter…
寄往伦敦的徽章研究学院
…addressed to College of Arms in London…
目的是要求确认 博堪普伯爵的头衔
…with a request to establish de Bleuchamp's claim to the title.
希拉里布雷爵士 他是学院里传说中的怪物
Sir Hilary Bray, the sable basilisk of the college…
他答应格布德会亲自去见他
…has replied to Gumbold, suggesting they meet in person.
我决定以追溯 我家族的徽章为耳目
I've taken the liberty of working with the college on this…
已与学院联络
…using an examination of my own family as cover.
我也正在研究纹章学的 技术性范畴
I've also been studying the technical side of heraldry.
- 希拉里布雷爵士 邦德长官 - 对了
- Sir Hilary Bray. Commander Bond. - Ah, yes, sir.
若他答应出席 我就装做是学院的代表
If he consents to a meeting, I could act as a college representative.
进来
Come.
- 午安 - 午安
- Good afternoon. - Good afternoon.
看 把你的大衣给我
Look at this. Let me take your coat.
这是汤姆士邦德的徽章 佩克汉男爵 1734年逝世
Arms of Sir Thomas Bond, Baronet of Peckham, died 1734.
黑银色山形臂章 三个金币
Argent on a chevron sable. Three bezants.
很好的格言：“世界是取之不尽”
Good motto, "The World is Not Enough."
- 菲迪亚干得不错 - 谢谢你
- Phidian's doing a splendid job. - Thank you, sir.
我们追溯 到奥塞邦爵士
We've traced your line to a Sir Otho le Bon…
他在1387年 在塞内特伯爵之下
…who held the manor of Wickhamsbreux by a knight's fee…
当骑士而维持威克布洛克的大官邸
…from the Earl of Thanet, 1387.
我们走运了
We're in luck.
格布德从布纳尔打电话来
Gumbold's telephoned from Bern…
说他的客人会来找我
…to say that his client will see me.
- 你是说我 - 对 是你
- You mean me. - Yes, you.
但邦德长官
But, Commander Bond…
若这是关乎国家的事
…I'm only able to countenance this deception…
我才可以答应瞒骗这件事
…on your assurance this matter is of national importance.
我没有夸大其辞 很高兴你愿意帮忙
I haven't exaggerated. We appreciate your help.
这段时间我安排了 去布列塔尼半岛
All right. During the deception period, I've arranged to go to Brittany.
我想去学拓印技术
I want to do some brass rubbings.
我该去哪里见他呢？
Where do I go for this meeting?
他们要我描述自己的样子
They want a description of myself.
- 说成是我的样子好了 - 对
- Tactfully adjusted to favor me. - Yes.
他们会告诉我 接我的时间和地点
They will send the time and place where I am to be…
这是他们的说法
…collected, as they put it.
这不是我们平常做的事 但在这情况下
It's not our sort of thing, but under the circumstances…
- 听起来他们起了疑心 - 不是可疑
- Sounds like they're suspicious. - No, not suspicious.
只是考虑周到
Just discreet.
我不反对煤付一千块的费用
There was no objection to my fee of 1000 guineas.
- 他们说的会不会是真的？- 暂时很难说
- Could their claim be genuine? - It's hard to say at this point.
要到我们肯定
We never like to speak until we're absolutely certain…
我方没有搞错
…that there's no error on our side…
或者是他们没有在伪造证据 才能下判断
…or forgery on theirs.
希望我达到你这么高的要求
I hope I meet your high standards.
有一个身体上的特征 可能对你有用
One helpful physical point might be…
真正的博堪普家族是没有耳垂的
…that the real de Bleuchamps are without earlobes.
这不是可以尽信的东西 但可能有帮助
It's not the sort of thing that we rely on, but it could help.
- 没有耳垂 - 你得邀请他到奥格斯堡
- No earlobes. - You might invite him to Augsburg.
他们祖先几代都在那里
They've been there for generations.
对 我想带他离开瑞士
Yes, I'd like to get him away from Switzerland.
- 希拉里布雷爵士？- 是的
- Sir Hilary Bray, baronet? - The same, dear lady.
我是尔犸邦特小姐 伯爵的私人秘书
I am Fraulein lrma Bunt, personal secretary to the count.
- 旅途愉快吗？- 挺难受的
- Have you had a good journey? - No, quite intolerable.
我很少旅游
I'm not a good traveler.
抱歉 格伦瑟会替你拿行李
I'm sorry. Grunther will take your luggage.
- 不用了 - 我替你拿
- No, I can manage. - I take it.
- 你来过瑞士没有？- 没有 小姐
- You know Switzerland, Sir Hilary? - I'm afraid not, Fraulein…
- 邦特 - 邦特
- Bunt. - Bunt.
一个有趣宗谱学家的名字
Interesting name for a genealogist.
- 你来自海军世家？- 海军？
- Are you from a naval family? - Naval?
是海上用的词汇 意思是鼓胀的帆
It's a nautical term, meaning the baggy or swollen parts of a sail.
- 请不要介意 - 有趣
- Nothing personal, of course. - Interesting.
- 你会说德语吗？- 不会
- You speak German? - I'm afraid not.
- 法语呢？- 还可以 我们去哪里呢？
- French? - A little. Where are we off to?
你不会觉得失望的地方 请
You will not be disappointed. Please?
好像地毯上的小虫吧？
Like the bugs in a rug, yes?
- 舒服吗？- 很舒服
- You are comfortable? - Yes, indeed, fraulein.
- 你真的很客气 - 是的
- Your kindness is quite overwhelming. - Good.
我们走了一半路程
So we are halfway.
现在我们坐飞机
Now we will have a little flight.
我从来没坐过这种飞机
I've never been in one of these.
请弄灭你的烟斗
You must your pipe knock off.
你指的是“弄熄”吧
"knock out", you mean.
对
I hope.
请小心别碰到头
Mind your head, Sir Hilary.
请系紧安全带
Please fasten your safety beIt.
我们到了阿尔卑斯山
Now, up into the Alps.
那是雪崩造成的破坏
That is avalanche damage.
你喜欢滑雪或者玩雪橇吗？
You enjoy the skiing or the bobsled perhaps?
我不爱做运动
I'm not a sporting man, fraulein.
即使是我精神很好的时候
Even when I'm at my best.
你晕机？
Do you feel the airsickness?
到那里为止是公众地方 这里以上是私人的
Up to there is for the public, and from here upwards it is private.
没有伯爵批准不能进入
No one may come through without permission from the count.
这是博堪普研究中心 研究敏感治疗的地方
There is the Bleuchamp Institute for Allergy Research.
- 哪种敏感？- 各种敏感
- What kind of allergies? - All of them.
比如说干草敏感症 对蠔的敏感
Like the hay fever, or the sickness caused by the oysters…
或是对吃肉的敏感
…or inability to eat meat.
伯爵是这方面的专家
The count is a great specialist in this field.
若可以踏足地上就好了
I'll be glad to get my feet on the ground.
不是地上 是冰上
Not ground. Ice.
我得告诉你 看见手枪我会很紧张
I should warn you, guns make me very nervous.
这些手枪用来对付 其他公司的间谍
They are to keep the spies from the chemical companies.
他们已经多次盗取我们的发明
Many times already they have tried to steal our discoveries.
我们的世界充满贪婪和欺诈
We live in a world of avarice and deceit.
- 起码这里没有贪婪 - 是吗？
- Here at least is no avarice. - Really?
博堪普研究中心是非营利的
The Bleuchamp lnstitute is not for profit, Sir Hilary.
伯爵只为人类而工作
The count does his work for the sake of mankind.
这很不错
I'm very happy to hear it.
他想留芳百世
He wants to leave his mark on the entire world.
- 典型的抱负 - 什么典型？
- Characteristic ambition. - Characteristic?
典型的人道主义者抱负
Of a true humanitarian.
这里以前是运动俱乐部 给公众使用
Formerly it was a sports club, open to the public.
现在这里为伯爵所有 作研究之用
Now it belongs to the count, who has given it to scientific research.
约瑟 布雷爵士会住四号房
Joseph, Sir Hilary Bray will take number four.
格伦瑟带你做身体检查以后 我会带你到房间
I'll show you there after Grunther takes you for medical examination.
- 我现在没事了 - 你是我们的贵宝
- I'm quite all right now. - You are our honored guest.
谢谢
Thank you.
你刚才坐直升机晕机
After your experience in the helicopter…
我们得确保你的状况正常
…we must make sure you are well again.
格伦瑟 带希拉里爵士见丰山医生
Grunther, take Sir Hilary to Dr. Von Sant.
喂？
Yes?
像平常一样招待他
Give him the usual comforts.
你有十分钟时间
You have 10 minutes…
然后带他去四号房
…and then take them to number four.
若你有什么需要 按这个铃
If you wish anything for your comfort, you must ring this…
服务生就会来
…and the attendant will come.
很细心 谢谢你
Very considerate. Thank you.
若你想出去 你也得按这个铃叫他开门
You must also ring for him to open the door when you wish to leave.
- 好复杂的安排 - 这可以防止病人在该休息时
- Complicated arrangement. - To stop patients leaving their rooms…
离开自己的房间
…when they should be resting.
伯爵认为不被打扰的休息很重要
The count believes very strongly in undisturbed rest.
我什么时候可以见他？我们要讨论很多事情
Prudent fellow. When can I see him? We have much to discuss.
他准备好就会来找你
He will send for you when he's ready.
现在请你在晚饭前跟我到 阿尔卑斯山房间
Meanwhile, I'd like you to join me in the Alpine room before dinner.
- 阿尔卑斯山房间？- 对 格伦瑟会来接你
- Alpine room? - Yes. Grunther will come for you.
- 七点钟好吗？- 好的
- Shall we say 7:00? - Thank you.
邦特小姐会接你
Fraulein Bunt will receive you.
希拉里爵士 请来跟我们的病人见面
Sir Hilary, please, come to meet our patients.
- 这是希拉里布雷爵士 次男爵 - 你好吗？
- This is Sir Hilary Bray, baronet. - How do you do?
他是著名的宗谱学家 要喝点什么？
He's a famous genealogist. You will have a drink, yes?
- 请坐 - 你好吗？
- Please, come and sit down. - How do you do?
谢谢
Thank you.
- 什么是次男爵？- 属于次等的爵位
- What is a baronet? - An inferior sort of baron.
- 真让人失望 - 其实
- Oh, how disappointing. - Well…
我不是说你次等 我是指那个头衔
Oh, I don't mean you're inferior. I mean the title is.
那宗谱学家是什么？
What's a gyn… genealogist? What is that?
是老人家的医生
An old people's doctor.
那他来医治邦特小姐？
So he's here to cure Fraulein Bunt?
小心 她的耳朵很灵的
Be careful. She's got ears like an elephant.
- 请问要喝点什么？- 麦芽酿的威士忌加水
- What will you drink, sir? - MaIt whiskey and branch water.
抱歉 我对你的头衔不敬
I'm sorry I was so rude about what a baronet is.
你说得没错
You gave a very accurate description.
- 先生 - 谢谢
- Sir. - Thank you.
偶尔有男士是个赏赐
It's a treat, having a man here for once.
你是说这里没有男人吗？
You mean there aren't any others?
只有职员吧 他们不算
Only the staff, and you can't really count them.
别谈论诊所的事情
Don't discuss the affairs of the clinic.
好 但宗谱学家是什么？没有人会告诉我吗？
Yes, but what is a genealogist? Will nobody tell me?
- 我乐意告诉你 - 真的？
- I would be pleased to tell you. - Well?
宗谱学是关于祖先和家庭的研究
Genealogy is all about ancestors and families.
你们都有可能跟皇室有连系
It could easily be that any one of you here is related to a royal house…
只要我们追溯得够远
…if only we could go back far enough to find out.
若你告诉我你的名字
Now, if you will tell me your names…
这里不用姓氏 这是诊所的规则
We do not use surnames here. It is a rule of the clinic.
抱歉 我并不知道
I'm so sorry. I didn't know that.
来吧 晚饭时间到了
Come, it's time for dinner.
我们的时间表很严紧 食疗法也一样
Our schedule is rather strict. So is our diet.
请你坐在海伦和鲁比中间
Please, if you will sit there between Helen and Ruby.
我很少跟年轻女孩相处
I've never had much to do with young ladies.
我为你预备了 皮兹格洛莉亚的牛排
I have ordered you a steak Piz Gloria.
- 希望你喜欢 - 谢谢 一定会
- I hope you enjoy it. - Thank you. I'm sure I will.
- 你来过耶诞节吗？- 可能会 假如
- Are you here for Christmas? - Well, I might be if…
- 我们离开前可以开个派对 - 我不喜欢这玩意
- We can have a party before we go! - That's not quite in my line.
味道很好！我以前不吃鸡肉
Delicious! I used to hate chicken.
吃鸡肉会让我过敏 你绝对不会想到在哪里
It used to make me break out all over. You'd be surprised where.
我对马铃薯也敏感 现在我爱死它们了
Potatoes did it to me. Now I adore them.
别谈论你们的病历
No medical histories, please.
各位 相信希拉里爵士乐意 向我们介绍徽章研究学院
Girls, I'm sure Sir Hilary would like to tell us about the College of Arms.
请告诉我们吧
Go on, Sir Hilary. Please tell us.
- 只要你们喜欢就行 - 请说吧
- If you'd really enjoy that. - Please. Yes!
- 我们一定会听 - 是吗？
- We promise to listen. - Would you?
来吧 告诉我们吧
Come on, tell us all about it.
纹章学院或者徽章研究学院
The Heralds' College, or College of Arms…
一共有十三位皇家的成员
…consists of 13 members of the royal household…
获国家委任管理
…appointed by the sovereign to superintend…
包括纹章集 宗谱图 礼仪和其他事务
…armourial, genealogical, ceremonial and other matters.
十三位成员分为三个类别
The 13 members are divided into three categories…
皇者 纹章部和追溯者
…kings, heralds and pursuivants.
他们的头衔和工作 都有悠久的历史
Their titles and offices are of great antiquity.
第一位纹章院院长的职位
Well, the first Clarenceux king of Arms…
创设于1334年
…was created in 1334…
1448年有第一个萨默塞特纹章
…and the first Somerset Herald in 1448.
当我们要核准一个徽章的时候
Now, when we authorize a coat of arms…
当中有许多有趣的图案
…it can include all sorts of funny things…
比如说半月形 升降闸门
…crescent moons, portcullises…
各种形状的野兽 线条 钱币
…beasts couchant and rampant, bars, bezants…
请问钱币是什么？
Please, what is "bezant"?
是一种金币
Gold balls.
我带来了一本徽章的图册 有关我的徽章
I brought a book on the subject with a picture of my coat of arms.
里面就有四个
Which includes four of them…
你有兴趣看吗？
…if you'd care to see them.
我有兴趣 我住在
I'd love to. I'm in room…
不用了 我会问他拿那本书
No, no. He will give the book to me.
再让你们传阅吧
I will pass it to everyone in turn.
- 这比较公平 - 当然 按你的意思办吧
- It is fairer like that. - Of course. If you think so, fraulein.
有什么不对吗？
Is anything the matter, Sir Hilary?
大概肩膀觉得有点僵硬
Just a slight stiffness coming on in the shoulder.
是因为身在高处所致吧
Due to the aItitude, no doubt.
伯爵想见你 格伦瑟会带你去
The count will see you. Grunther will take you.
谢谢 不好意思 我离开一下
Thank you. Please excuse me, ladies.
祝你们的敏感都早日康复吧
May all your allergies be swiftly cured.
- 真是个好男人 - 很可爱
- What a nice man. - Sweet!
我知道他对什么敏感
I know what he's allergic to.
钱币
Bezants…
消毒器
Antisepsis.
请在这里等一下
Please wait here.
- 晚安 希拉里爵士 - 晚安
- Good evening, Sir Hilary. - Good evening.
我是巴达哈博堪普伯爵
BaIthazar, Count de Bleuchamp.
我就是来调查你的爵位
If you'll forgive me, that's what I'm here to find out.
是来确定所有事情
To confirm. There can be no doubt of the truth.
- 请坐 - 若是没有怀疑
- Please, sit down. - If there were no doubt…
我也不会被派到这里来
…I'm sure I would not have been sent.
既然你来了我会让你了解清楚
Well, since you are here, I'll make everything very plain to you.
首先 我一出生就没有耳垂
To begin with, I was born without earlobes…
这是众所周知的博堪普家族特征
…a well-known congenital distinction of Bleuchamp ancestry…
好像哈布斯堡家族的嘴唇 或者美第奇的鹰鼻子吧
…like the Hapsburg lip or the hawk nose of the Medicis.
当然 但即使你是博堪普家的人
Granted, but the fact that you're a de Bleuchamp…
你也不一定是伯爵
…doesn't make you the reigning count.
我感觉得到我是贵族血统
I feel it in my blood and in my bones.
我想学院需要更多的证明
I'm afraid the college will require more concrete proofs.
他们也应该有这些证明
And it shall have them.
我已经预备了有关的文件
I have assembled all the relevant documents…
头衔证书 生死证明书
…title deeds, certificates of birth and death.
我会送到你的房间给你鉴证
I'll send them to your room for authentication.
有任何需要 告诉邦特小姐就行
You've only to ask Fraulein Bunt for anything you require.
- 你在这里舒服吗？- 不错 但你的诊所让我迷惑
- Are you comfortable here? - Yes, but puzzled by your clinic.
许多先驱者作为 都让凡人感到迷惑
The methods of the great pioneers often puzzle conventional minds.
我发明了治疗敏感的方法
I've devised a cure for allergies…
重点在于
…which depends on holding an unusual…
取得心理的平衡
…and delicate psychological balance.
所以我给病人特别的治疗环境
So I must impose rather special conditions on my patients.
还有你的实验室？
And your laboratories?
治疗不只是心理方面的
The cure is not entirely psychological, Sir Hilary.
我们准备了特别的疫苗
There are special vaccines to be prepared.
我们会为个别病例改造疫苗
Vaccines which must be modified to suit each individual case.
所以我很忙
So I'm a very busy man…
不一定可以给你太多时间
…and I cannot spare you as much time as I might wish.
要确定你是否博堪普家族的人
To be confirmed as Count de Bleuchamp…
你得给我多一点时间
…you must give me some of your time.
我需要你在生的亲杯 父母和祖父母的详细资料
I need details of your living relatives, parents and grandparents.
- 你看那些文件就够了 - 可解答问题 但不能找出真相
- The documents you will see… - Can answer questions, but not all.
还有一件事情
Oh, one more thing.
若你能跟我一起去奥格斯堡 会有帮助
It would help if you could accompany me to visit Augsburg.
- 奥格斯堡？- 那是博堪普家族的故乡
- Augsburg? - The de Bleuchamps' ancestral home.
在那里教堂有他们祖坟
There are tombs in the cathedral…
市政府还有重要的记录
…and important records in the city archives.
若你能亲自跟我一起去
You there to assist with your personal knowledge…
暂时还不方便
That may not be convenient for some time…
但我的名衔一定会获得核实
…but my title shall be recognized.
你可以开始进行初步的调查
You may proceed with your preliminary research.
我会马上开始
I'll be happy to start immediately.
谢谢 格伦瑟先生
Thank you, Herr Grunther.
希拉里爵士
Sir Hilary!
我给你带了那本书
I brought you the book.
- 是解图集吗？- 不要开灯
- The illustrated book? - No, don't turn it on.
- 我想看看那些图画 - 你自己就是一幅画
- I want to see the pictures. - You're a picture yourself…
在火光下更加明艳动人
…and twice as lovely in the firelight.
真有趣 你假装不喜欢女孩
You are funny, pretending not to like girls.
我平常不喜欢的
Well, I don't usually.
但你与众不同
But you're not usual.
那口红让人遐思 你也是
That lipstick was an inspiration. So are you.
希拉里爵士
Oh, Sir Hilary.
叫我礡利吧
Call me "Hilly."
礡利
Hilly.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
鲁比巴特利特 从兰开夏来的
Ruby Bartlett, from Lancashire.
- 应该说是莫克姆湾 - 你怎么到这里来的？
- Morecambe Bay, actually. - How did you get here?
我们得现在就谈吗？
Do we have to talk about that now?
是真的
It's true!
你怎么到这里来的？
How did you get here?
我对鸡非常敏感
I had this awful allergy about chickens.
我家有个鸡场
My family has a chicken farm…
每次在那里工作时 我都难受得要命了
…and whenever I had to work on it I nearly died.
有位专家说有一所瑞士的诊所
A specialist said there was a Swiss clinic…
因为在做研究 所以会免费给予医治
…where they cured you, free, because they're doing research.
继续吧 不 我是说诊所的事
Go on. No, about the clinic, I mean.
那专家安排我 在伦敦跟邦特小姐见面
Well, the specialist had me meet Fraulein Bunt in London…
她说我的病情很特别
…and she said I had a very interesting case.
她说得对
How right she was.
礡利
Oh, Hilly!
别理它
Oh, bother!
不 这是治疗的一部分
No, Hilly. It's part of the cure.
七号录音带
Cassette number seven.
八号录音带
Number eight.
还记得你刚来的时候
Do you remember when you first came here…
你多讨厌鸡？
…how you hated chickens?
一见到鸡就会很不舒服？
How you were sick when you even saw one?
但现在一切都过去了
But all that is over now…
因为我让你知道 那是多无聊的
…for I have shown you how foolish it was…
而你也快痊愈了
…and your cure is nearly done.
我教你去喜欢鸡
I have taught you to love chickens…
喜欢鸡肉和他的叫声
…to love their flesh, their voice.
你快痊愈了
Yes, your cure is nearly done.
很快你就会回家去
And soon you will go home…
去找你喜欢的鸡
…to look after the chickens that you love so much.
你有一点喜欢我 是吗 礡利？
You do love me just a little, don't you, Hilly?
- 走之前要学会一件事情 - 鲁比
- Learn one more thing before you go. - Ruby.
我会教你怎么特别照顾他们
I must teach you how to give them special care.
我会告诉你怎么做
I will tell you what to do.
- 鲁比 醒来吧 - 我会告诉你什么时候做
- Ruby, wake up. - I will tell you when.
和怎么做
I will tell you how.
而你办完我教你的事以后
And after you've done what I teach you…
你会永远的忘记
…you will forget it forever.
永远忘记
Forever.
礡利 你这魔鬼
Hilly, you old devil.
- 是我 - 真想不到
- It is me, yes? - Quite undeniably, yes.
你怎么出来的？
How did you get out?
用指甲刀 轻而易举
With a fingernail file. It's so easy.
我不会知道的
I wouldn't know.
- 我来看你的解图集 - 好主意
- I come to see the book, the pictures? - Jolly good idea.
但我放在哪里呢？
Now, where did I put it?
刚才好像还在的
I had it a few moments ago.
- 不如开灯吧？- 不要
- Perhaps if we turn on the light? - No.
你自己就是一幅画
You're a picture yourself.
在火光下更加明艳动人
And twice as lovely in the firelight.
- 但是 爵士 - 礡利
- But, Sir Hilary… - Hilly.
但你说你不喜欢女孩的 礡利
But I think you do not like girls, Hilly.
我平时不喜欢的 但你与众不同
Usually, I don't, but you're not usual.
你来这里惹人遐思
Coming here was an inspiration…
你也是
…and so are you.
注定要这样子
You'll need to be.
- 你说什么？- 我们如此相遇像个奇迹
- What you say? - A miracle, our meeting like this.
我连你的名字也不知道
I don't even know your name.
我晚点会告诉你
I tell you all about myself later.
明早吧
In the morning.
喂
Hey.
可以带我到山顶上去吗？
What about a lift to the top?
这是不行的 上面是私人地方
It is not permitted. All is private.
但上面有餐馆 也有个运动俱乐部
But surely there's a restaurant, a club up there.
我看过广告
I've seen them advertised.
- 现在都关门了 - 什么时候的事？
- It's all closed now. - Since when?
- 我真的看过广告 - 你误会了
- I've seen them advertised. - You are mistaken.
那是几星期前的事 现在已经没有了
For many weeks, they are finished.
但我还是想到山顶去
But I'd still like to get to the top.
从这里开始 上面都是禁区
From here up, it's forbidden!
是私人的地方 都关门了
Private! Closed!
好的
All right.
轮到我了
It's my turn now.
- 希拉里爵士 - 你早
- Sir Hilary! - Good morning.
你早 你昨晚僵硬的肩膀
Good morning. Your stiffness of last night…
现在没事了吗？
…it is all gone?
- 起码暂时没事吧？- 跟我们一起玩冰上掷石游戏
- For the time being. - Then come and do curling with us.
- 这消耗体力吗？- 不
- Won't that be frightfully energetic? - No.
- 我示范给你看 - 也许你想教我
- We'll show you. - Perhaps you'd teach me.
- 开始吧 - 我们对你期望很高
- Have a go. - We expect great things of you.
我们快要走了 我要见你
We're leaving very soon. I must see you.
今晚八点
Eight o'clock tonight.
那男的一个人吗？
And the man was alone?
- 各位早 - 你早
- Good morning, ladies. - Good morning!
希拉里爵士 你早 你的调查如何？
Good morning, Sir Hilary. How's your research?
不错 看来十分顺利
Riveting, and very promising too.
我没听过那么荒谬的事
I've never heard anything so ridiculous in all my life!
爬山也算犯法吗？
Since when is climbing a criminal offence?
不好意思 皮兹格洛莉亚是私人产业
Excuse me. Piz Gloria, sir, is private property.
整个阿尔卑斯山也是吗？真荒谬
The whole bloody Alp? Ridiculous!
这里有警告牌 我的随从也警告过你
There are many signs, and my servant warned you down at the station.
到你抛了
Your throw, I think it is.
我刚抛了 而且造成了混乱
I had my throw. Made a mess of it, I'm afraid.
这不算 你可以再抛
That didn't count. You can throw again.
- 好 继续 - 你很有礼貌
- Yes, go on. - Very civil of you, fraulein.
你们这些笨蛋无权向我开火 你究竟是谁？
… doesn't entitle these goons to shoot at me. Who the hell are you?
我是这个中心的总裁
I am the director of this institute.
我会送你下山 以后别再骚扰我们
You'll be sent back down and will refrain from troubling us again!
那我的东西呢？
What about my belongings?
- 晚点会送给你 - 但那是我的东西
- They will be sent later. - But they're mine!
这里的规则必须严格执行
We have certain rules which must be observed.
- 我会向政府投诉 - 再见
- The authorities will hear about it! - Good day.
总裁 我想应该叫你伯爵
Director… Or count, as I think I can now safely say…
今天下午我想休息 请你让我搭吊车下去
I thought I'd take the afternoon off, so if you send the car down…
但今早你已经休息了
But you've already had the morning off.
我需要一点新鲜空气 这是辛苦的工作
Must have a bit of fresh air. Those ancestors are hard work.
所以徽章研究学院的薪水优厚
And the College of Arms is being very well paid.
- 若你要这样 - 我真的要这样
- If you put it like that… - I do put it like that.
我给你看看我的研究结果 然后马上到奥格斯堡
I'll show you what I've done, then we'll plan the trip to Augsburg…
- 尽快完成工作 - 在耶诞节？
- …and finish it. - Over Christmas?
耶诞节时资料库不会关门吗？
The archives will be closed, will they not?
来吧 按摩时间到了
Come, girls, it's time for our massage.
今天的冰上掷石游戏时间完毕
Girls, that is enough curling for today.
- 今晚我要见你 - 九点钟好吗？
- I must see you tonight. - Nine o'clock?
十点钟？我要回去工作
Ten? Well, back to work.
想不到为何会大排长龙
You've no idea how it's piling up.
鲁比 是礡利
Ruby! It's me, Hilly.
礡利知道鲁比要走好难过
Hilly's so sad that Ruby's leaving.
那老母牛有没有告诉你
Has that old cow told you?
幸会 小姐
Fancy meeting you here, fraulein!
耶诞节快乐 007
Merry Christmas, 007.
我是希拉里布雷爵士
I'm Sir Hilary Bray.
不 邦德先生
No, no, Mr. Bond.
纹章学院受尊敬的男次爵
Respectable baronets from the College of Heralds…
不会在诊所勾引女病人
…do not seduce female patients in clinics.
而且不会搞错资料细节
On the other hand, they do get their professional details right.
博堪普家族的祖坟 不是在奥格斯堡的教堂
The Bleuchamp tombs are not in the Augsburg Cathedral, as you said…
而是在圣安娜柯奇 希拉里布雷爵士应该知道的
…but in the Saint Anna kirche. Sir Hilary Bray would've known.
你说错了
A small slip.
007要变成宗谱学家 得准备更详尽的道具
Takes more than a few props to turn 007 into a herald.
你也不要以为剪掉耳垂 就可以变成伯爵
It'll take more than cutting off your earlobes to turn you into a count.
也许我还可以给你一点惊喜 但你再没什么惊喜给我了
I may yet surprise you, but I'm afraid you have no surprises left for me.
我完全知道你的行动
I know all about your mission, Mr. Bond.
你的同事
Your colleague…
一个爱爬山的健谈者
Such a keen climber, such a brilliant conversationalist…
他走以前已经告诉我们
…before he left us.
- 当然他会向上级报告我在哪里 - 我很怀疑这点
- Of course he reported where I am. - I doubt that.
不管如何 没有人来救你的了
In any case, no one's going to come to your rescue.
几个小时内 联合国会收到耶诞佳音
In a few hours, the United Nations will receive my yuletide greetings:
他们会知道 我拥有了一种科学技术
The information that I now possess the scientific means to control…
足以破坏整个地球经济
…or to destroy the economy of the whole world.
到时有更重要事要烦恼 你已不重要了
People will have more important things to think about than you.
如果他们相信你的话
If they believe your threat.
会的 我随时预备好作出示范
They will. In any case, I have prepared a demonstration.
还记得去年夏天
Remember that disagreeable outbreak…
在英国突然爆发的口蹄病吗？
…of foot-and-mouth disease in England last summer?
我可以仔细向你们示范
Well, I shall instruct them, in very convincing terms…
我怎么安排这种病诞生 自从那次以后我的能力也增强了
…exactly how I arranged that. And my capacity has improved since.
防敏感疫苗？
Allergy vaccines?
是细菌 细菌武器
Bacteria. Bacteriological warfare.
还不只这样
With a difference.
自去年夏天起 我们最大的突破
Our great breakthrough since last summer…
就是发明了一种病毒
…has been the confection of a certain…
- 奥米加病毒 - 可以引致不育
- …Virus Omega. - Infertility.
使动植物都会完全不育
Total infertility in plants and animals.
这可不是只让几种动物生病 邦德先生
Not just disease in a few herds, Mr. Bond…
也不是只会损失一些农作物
…or the loss of a single crop…
而是完全灭绝一切 永远灭绝
…but the destruction of a whole strain, forever…
整个大陆的生物都会消失
…throughout an entire continent.
若还达不到我的要求
If my demands are not met…
我会继续有计划进行灭绝
…I shall proceed with the systematic extinction…
直到全世界的动植物都消失为止
…of whole species of cereals and livestock all over the world.
包括人类？
lncluding, I suppose, the human race?
我想不会吧 邦德先生
I don't think, do you, Mr. Bond…
联合国不会让这事发生吧
…the UN will let it come to that.
他们的科学家分析过 奥米加病毒样本以后
Not after their scientists analyze a small sample…
就不会让这事发生
…of Virus Omega they have received.
流行性不育病毒
Epidemics of sterility.
到时候万物没有生育 连种子也不会发芽
Nothing is born. No seed even begins to sprout.
- 他们定会找到解毒方法 - 当然
- They'll find an antidote. - Of course!
但要我给他们足够的时间才行
If I give them enough time.
他们会有时间
They'll have time.
他们收到警告 就会想办法解决它
Once they're warned, you'll have a problem dispensing it.
我已有对付方法
That problem has already been solved.
我已经训练了一批死亡天使
I have been training my own special "Angels of Death."
是那些女孩
Those girls.
对 还有许多像她们的人
Those girls, and many others like them.
但究竟怎么行动？
But exactly how?
这是我的秘密
That will remain my secret.
你这次行动的酬金是多少？
How many hundred millions do you want for your services this time?
这次的条件是另类的
This time? This time, the price is of another kind.
你也会觉得很特别
You'll be amused when you know what.
暂时你还会留在这里当我的贵宝
In the meanwhile, I will keep you here as my guest.
你可以帮我说服当局
You'll be very useful in helping to convince the authorities…
证明我所言非虚
…that I mean what I say…
言出必行
…and I'll do what I claim.
来吧 我带你去你的新住处
Come. Let me show you to your new quarters.
相信你得在这里多待一会儿
You're likely to be with us for some time, Mr. Bond.
首先
So first…
控制一下你的不驯性格
…a little therapy to soothe your restless nature.
真可怜 他也是不听话的
Poor fellow. He was restless too.
你这顽固的英国人 你真的太喜欢运动了
You perverse British, how you love your exercise.
每年几十个业余爬山者 都有同样的下场
Every year, dozens of amateur climbers end in the same predicament.
变成的蜡像给游客一个警惕
A kind of waxworks show for morbid tourists.
好朋友
Dear, dear me.
邦德先生 我们把你送回文明社会前
Now, now. Now, Mr. Bond, you must learn to be absolutely calm…
请你保持冷静
…before we can accept you back into polite society.
礼物
Presents!
是饯行礼物
Going-away presents…
伯爵亲自送给你们的
…from the count himself, in appreciation.
- 我想现在就打开它 - 不
- I want to open mine now. - No.
等其他人一起来拆礼物会更好玩
It is more fun to open them all together, yes?
请坐 我们等其他人来
Please sit down. We will wait for the others.
看 有礼物
Look, look, look!
耶诞节前夕的蛋酒 我好像回到家里了
Eggnog on Christmas Eve. Just like home!
这是为我们而设的欢送派对
It is a treat for the going-away party.
- 祝你身体健康 - 干杯
- Your very good heaIth, my dears. - Cheers! Cheers!
可以治愈你们真好
It has been so nice to cure you.
这个平安夜派对挺特别的
It has something special in it for the Holy Night celebration.
你们将会踏上归途
And now you're going on a journey. A journey home.
但现在你们得休息一下
But first you must rest for a while.
休息
Rest. Rest.
Rest…
我会告诉你什么时候做和怎么做
I will tell you when, and I will tell you how…
但这是我们的秘密
…but it must be our secret.
是你跟我的秘密
Yours and mine. Our secret.
而你办完我教你的事以后
And after you've done what I teach you…
你会永远的忘记
…you will forget it forever.
永远 永远忘记
Forever. Forever.
现在你可以再睁开眼睛
And now you may open your eyes again.
每个人都有一份礼物
Each of you has been given a present…
好可爱的小礼物
…such a prettily wrapped present.
现在可以打开它了 打开它
Now is the time to open them. Open them.
看 它们多漂亮
You see, they're beautiful…
你好想知道里面是什么
…and you're longing to know what's inside.
你什么都可以用 除了喷雾器以外
You may use anything but the atomizer…
你绝对不能碰这个喷雾器
…which you must never touch, never…
除非我告诉你什么时候在哪里用
…until I tell you how and where to use it.
打开粉盒
Open the compact.
调节下面的控制器
Adjust the bottom control.
每晚十二点 你要单独一个人
Every night at exactly 12:00, you must be alone…
开着接收器
…so you can switch on that receiver…
接听我的声音
…and listen for my voice.
我会告诉你要做什么 我会告诉你什么时候做
I'll tell you what to do, I will tell you when…
和怎么做
…and I will tell you how.
听完我说话以后
After you've heard what I say…
盖上镜子把接收器收起来
…push the mirror back to conceal the receiver again.
现在就把它关上
Push it back now and close the case.
现在再休息吧 休息
Now rest again. Rest.
休息
Rest.
几分钟后你就会醒来
In a few minutes, you will wake up.
你会忘了我刚才说的话
You will not remember what I just told you…
直到你回到家里
…until you return home.
- 好漂亮的礼物 - 我不太舒服
- What a lovely present. - I don't feel too good.
各位 我们赶时间
Please, girls, we are in a hurry.
耶诞节快乐
Merry Christmas.
也许我该把你包成一份礼物
Maybe you should've been gift-wrapped.
放照明弹
Flare.
- 他想到村里去 - 到断崖前拦截他
- He's making for the village. - Head him off at the precipice.
笨蛋
ldiot!
各位再见了 耶诞节快乐
Goodbye, girls. Merry Christmas.
新年快乐
And a happy New Year.
再见！
Goodbye!
Bye!
走吧
Come on.
詹姆斯
James.
甜心 你怎么了？
Darling, what is it?
- 有人追杀我 - 我可以帮你吗？
- There's people after me. - Can I help?
- 有车吗？- 在外面
- Have you got a car? - Outside.
我们得离开这里
Let's get out of here.
紧跟着我
Stay close to me.
快到了
Not far now.
到车门边趴下
Near-side door.
- 也许他没看见我 - 我不肯定
- Maybe he didn't see me. - I wouldn't go "Banco!" on that.
要放弃坏习惯了？
Giving up bad habits?
- 我们该去哪里？- 到最近的邮局跟伦敦联络
- Where are we heading? - Nearest post office to contact London.
我认得卡德基克 他们干嘛要追你？
I know, Feldkirch. Why are they looking for you?
他们要杀我
I suspect they're trying to kill me.
开车
Drive on!
没有人追来了
No sign of them yet.
也没有人道谢
Or of someone saying thank you.
谢谢 崔西 你的眼睛好明亮
Thank you, Tracy. You've got sharp eyes and beautiful…
还有漂亮的耳垂 你在皮兹格洛莉亚干嘛？
Earlobes. What were you doing so near Piz Gloria?
我找到了新的兴趣
Now I have a new interest in life.
是冬季运动吗？真有益
Winter sports? Very wholesome.
是个冬季运动员 爸爸告诉我在哪里找他
Just one winter sportsman, and Papa told me where to find him.
专心驾驶吧
Just keep my mind on your driving.
很好 我们到了 快走
Good. There it is, James. Hurry.
詹姆斯
James!
向他们开火
Shoot at them!
干得好
Good girl.
那里的人群可以分散他们的注意力
That crowd might discourage them.
碰巧是交通繁忙时间
Looks like we've hit the rush hour.
我们得停住他们
We must stop them!
怎么能出去呢？
How do we get out?
把他撞走
Knock him out of the way!
希望我的大车尾撑的住
I hope my big end will stand up to this.
我们怎么出去？
James! How do we get out?
一直向前走
Keep straight!
- 我们可以从那里出去 - 但愿如此
- We can get out there. - If you say so.
连奖品也没拿就走了
We didn't even stop for the prize.
这就是我们现在需要的
I told you that crowd would discourage them.
That's all we need right now.
开进那里
Pull in there.
继续前进吧 我去开门
keep moving. I'll open the doors.
抱歉 伯爵夫人 这里环境太差了
Sorry about the accommodations, contessa.
我们该先打电话来订房
We should have rung ahead and booked.
可惜我没有接上伦敦那边
If only I'd got through to London.
- 起码你还有机会 - 但什么时候呢？
- At least you'll get another chance. - But when?
先休息一下 我们得尽快上路
Let's get some rest. We'll push on as soon as we can.
起码这里满干爽的
At least it's dry.
在上面究竟发生了什么事？
What really went on up there, James?
我还在进行特务工作
Her Majesty's Secret Service is still my job.
但暂时你什么也做不了 对吗？
But there isn't anything you can do about it at the moment, is there?
不
No.
那你干嘛还在想呢？
Then why are you thinking about it now?
我没有
I'm not.
我在想我们俩的事
I'm thinking about us.
崔西 特务不能有后顾之忧
Tracy, an agent shouldn't be concerned with anything but himself.
我明白 我们和以前一样好了
I understand. We'll just have to go on the way we are.
不
No.
我要找别的工作
I'll have to find something else to do.
真的吗？
Are you sure, James?
我爱你
I love you.
我再找不到像你这样的女孩
I know I'll never find another girl like you.
嫁给我吧？
Will you marry me?
你是认真的吗？
Do you mean it?
是的
I mean it.
詹姆斯邦德先生和太太
Mr. and Mrs. James Bond.
住在团比威尔斯的洋槐路上
Of Acacia Avenue, Tunbridge Wells.
那贝尔格莱维广场呢？
How about Belgrave Square?
或者罗马的维亚文尼图
Or the Via Veneto, Rome.
巴黎吧 方便到图克特
Paris, convenient for Le Touquet.
摩纳哥 方便到瑞尼尔
Monaco, handy for the Rainiers.
这地方要多少钱？
I wonder how much they're asking for this place.
等我们结婚那天才适合做这事
The proper time for this is our wedding night.
这是我的新年计划
And that's my New Year's resolution.
- 听你的 亲爱的 - 你睡这里
- Whatever you say, darling. - And that is yours.
晚安 崔西
Good night, Tracy.
晚安 詹姆斯
Good night, James.
新年还没到
It's not New Year yet.
- 詹姆斯 - 继续走吧
- James! - keep going!
- 轻而易举 - 干得好
- Simple! - Good girl.
他真大胆
He had lots of guts.
（雪崩地区）
你们三个继续追
You three keep going.
往树林去
Let's head for the trees!
- 詹姆斯 - 继续走吧
- James! - keep going!
崔西 抓紧我
Tracy, cling onto me!
这个坟墓够深到 不能让007再动了吧
A grave deep enough, I think, to prevent even 007 from walking.
抓那女孩来
Get the girl.
是联合国来电 红色扰频器
United Nations, sir. Red scrambler.
我是M
M here.
对 我们已按指示准备就绪
Yes, we're standing by as instructed.
我知道
I understand.
谢谢你
Thank you, sir.
还没宣布最终决定
No decision has been announced yet.
当然 这消息会完全被封锁了
Of course, it's a total news blackout.
我的线民很清楚情况
But my informant was very plain.
- 有多清楚呢？- 他们要向布费德妥协
- How plain, sir? - They're going to buy Blofeld off.
坐
Sit down.
- 条件呢？- 特赦
- And the price? - Amnesty.
洗脱过去的所有罪名
A full pardon for all past crimes.
还有确认他的头衔
Official recognition of his title…
所以他可以 以博堪普伯爵的名义退休
…when he retires into private life as Count de Bleuchamp.
他看来很执着爵位
He seems to set great store by that.
挺有趣 他很势利
A very curious thing, snobbery.
- 什么时候决定是否成交？- 布费德希望
- When will they conclude the deal? - Blofeld wants to know…
明晚十二点前知道最后的决定
…the council's decision not later than midnight the day after tomorrow.
我们有时间先到 皮兹格洛莉亚用武力摧毁
That gives us time to get to Piz Gloria first. In force.
不 007 我的指示很清楚了
No, 007. My instructions are clear.
破坏研究中心 还有布费德和他的病毒
Destroy the institute and destroy Blofeld and his virus with it.
这因为太冒险而被否决了 还有那些女孩
It's been rejected as too risky. Those girls…
谁知道她们有多少人 更别说在哪里了
God knows how many, let alone where.
若破坏了中心的通讯控制台
If we destroy the center of communication controlling the girls…
那些女孩干不了什么
…they can do nothing.
我有我的命令 你有你的 算了吧
I have my orders, you have yours. Forget it.
那个帮我逃走的女孩 我们怎能不管她？
The girl who helped me escape, we just leave her?
本部门不理会你的私人问题
This department is not concerned with your personal problems.
这部门欠她一个人情 她救了我
This department owes her a debt. She saved my life.
疯人院行动已经完了
Operation Bedlam is dead.
- 你明白吗？- 明白
- Do you understand? - Yes, sir.
我知道
I understand.
这是马克安跩哥 跩哥建筑公司的主席
Your call to Marc Draco, head of Draco Construction.
- 跩哥？- 我就是 你是谁？
- Hello, Draco? - Yes, who is it?
- 詹姆斯邦德 - 天啊 是你
- James Bond. - Thank God, James.
我想你参与一桩破坏性的行动
I'd like to interest you in a demolition deal…
需要配备航空用品
…that requires aerial activity to install equipment.
我们真的可以 在上面找到崔西？
Are you sure we're going to find Teresa when we get up there?
我颇肯定的 如果不是 我们也有个原因要上去
I'm pretty certain. If not, there's a good reason for going anyway.
明白了 好像是十字军
So you've explained. Quite a crusade.
是时候庆祝了
It is a time for celebration.
也许 等他们答应才庆祝吧
Perhaps, if they agree.
他们不能再做些什么 你知道 他们也知道
They can do nothing else and you know it, and they know it.
你想要的我都可以给你
I shall be able to offer you anything your heart could wish for.
要牺牲多少性命呢？
Paid for with how many lives?
崔西 别那么嚣张
Oh, come now, Tracy, don't be so proud.
你爸爸的财产 也不是完全合法得来的
Your own father's profession is not entirely within the law.
他的同业也有很奇特的方式 保持秘密
His brotherhood also have exotic ways to keep it a closed shop.
巴塞尔指呼叫不明飞机
Basle approach calling unidentified aircraft.
你进入了受管制的领空
You're flying in controlled airspace.
我们没有你的飞行计划
We have no flight plan filed on you.
有些人不知我们是十字军战士
I think some people don't know we're crusaders.
若你能讨好我
Now, if you're very, very nice to me…
我会让你成为我的伯爵夫人
…I could make you my countess.
我已经是个伯爵夫人了
But I'm already a countess.
若你让我不快 我一定会让你很难受
Whereas if you displease me, I can promise you a very different estate.
- 对不起 - 怎么了？
- Excuse me, sir. - Yes?
请你听一听无线电的讯号
There is something on the radio you should hear.
- 抱歉 - 苏黎世航空中心
- Excuse me. - This is Zurich information…
呼叫不明飞机 请回覆
…calling unidentified aircraft. Over.
苏黎世航空中心呼叫不明飞机
This is Zurich information calling unidentified aircraft.
- 怎么样？- 他们有三架直升机
- Well? - That helicopter is one of three.
- 没有一架回覆 - 然后呢？
- None have answered air control. - And?
附近有可疑飞机
There are suspect aircraft in the vicinity.
机长的姓名及目的地 请回覆
… pilot's name and destination. Over.
苏黎世 这是F G S飞机
Zurich, this is Foxtrot, Gulf, Sierra, leading Red Cross helicopter flight…
将红十字会医疗物资到意大利
…carrying Red Cross medical supplies to Italy.
有什么问题？
What's the trouble? Over.
我们没有你的航班记录
We have no record of your flight plan.
完毕
Over.
重复 我们没有你的航班记录
I repeat, we have no record of your flight plan or registration. Over.
那你该更新你的记录
Then your registrations must be out-of-date. Over.
F G S飞机 这是苏黎世航空中心
Foxtrot, Gulf, Sierra, this is Zurich information.
你得在苏黎世降落和报告
You must land at Zurich and report.
重复 在苏黎世降落和报告
I say again, land at Zurich and report.
- 完毕 - 你想谋杀吗？
- Over. - Do you wish to commit murder?
我告诉你 这是救援飞机
I told you, this is a mercy flight…
带着血浆和急救用品
…carrying blood plasma and emergency equipment…
给意大利洛维戈
…for the victims of the Italian flood disaster…
水灾的灾民
…at Rovigo.
重复
I repeat:
这是救援飞机 明白吗？
Mercy flight. You understand me?
- G号机 S号机？- 怎么了？
- Gulf, Sierra? - Yes?
是苏黎世 你们可以继续前进了 通话完毕
Zurich. Very well, you may proceed. Out.
看到没？根本没什么
You see? It is nothing.
看来摆平了
Seems to have settled it.
若我们其中一个了回程受阻
In case one or both of us is delayed on the way home…
最好有个集合点
…it's better to have a rendezvous for later.
我们没功夫说这些 因为我们被跟踪了
Before we start getting sentimental, I think we're being followed.
我在考虑你的建议
I've been thinking about your proposition.
多说一点吧
Please, tell me more.
这是空军控制中心 我们没有你的航班资料
This is military air control. There is no record of your mission.
改变航道到苏黎世降落
AIter course to Zurich and land.
我们已经派遣战机拦截
Fighters have been dispatched to intercept you. Over.
你最好再仔细查阅你的记录
I suggest you check your records again, carefully. Over.
重复 到苏黎世降落
I repeat, return to Zurich and land. Over.
跟日内瓦的红十字会联络吧
Check with Geneva. Check with the Red Cross in Geneva.
请你撤回你的战机
Meanwhile, call off your air force.
- 我的乘客感到不适了 - F G S号飞机
- It is making my passengers sick. - Foxtrot, Gulf, Sierra…
- 机上有乘客吗？- 当然
- …you are carrying passengers? - Of course I am.
是国际知名的报界代表
Distinguished representatives of the world press.
他们受够了你的无理对待 我也是
They've had enough of your nonsense. So have I.
通话完毕
Over and out.
我有很多话要说 但以后我们还有很多时间
There's a lot more to tell, but there will be plenty of time later.
带我到阿尔卑斯山房间
Take me to the Alpine room.
在这里不舒服吗？
Are you unhappy here?
我想看日出
I want to see the dawn.
你真浪漫
So poetic a pleasure.
当帕里斯抱着海伦观赏日出
What were all the world's charms to mighty Paris…
到底有多陶醉呢？
…when he found that first dawn in the arms of his Helen?
什么时候才等到回覆？
When do you expect the signal accepting your terms?
今晚十二点以前
Any time before midnight tonight.
晨曦 世上之光 你的曙光
"Thy dawn, O master of the world, thy dawn.
因为你 阳光照遍草原
For thee, the sunlight creeps across the lawn.
因为你 船儿沉入大海
For thee, the ships are drawn down to the waves.
因为你 世界充满奴隶
For thee, the markets throng with myriad slaves.
因为你 铁捶捶击在铁钻
For thee, the hammer on the anvil rings.
你让
For thee…
享乐的诗人歌唱
…the poet of beguilement sings."
- 直升机 - 防守各处
- Helicopters! An attack! - Get all positions covered!
监视她
Look to the girl!
- 崔西 - 感谢主
- Tracy! Darling! - Thank God, Teresa!
詹姆斯 等一下
James, wait!
看见手枪我会很紧张
Guns make me nervous!
你尽了你的本分 带她到安全的地方
You've done your share. Get her to safety.
来吧 走吧
Come on! Let's go!
你来
And you!
马上接驳引爆线 走吧
Get the circuit set up now! Let's go!
- 两边都铺好了？- 是的
- All points covered? - Yes, sir.
预备好引爆？
All set to blow?
设定在五分十秒后爆炸
The fuse is set for exactly five minutes and 10 seconds.
这里会永久尘封
The place will be sealed forever.
那英国人有时间逃生吗？
Will that give the Englishman time to get out?
他也知道时间的
He knows the schedule.
- 你去哪里？- 詹姆斯在哪里？
- Where are you going? - Where's James?
- 他晚点会加入我们 - 不能丢下他
- He'll join us soon. - But we can't leave him!
- 他不需要你的帮忙 - 没有他我不走
- He doesn't need help! - I won't go without him!
你一定要走
You'll have to!
孩子不打不成器
Spare the rod and spoil the child!
五 四 三
Five, four, three…
二 一 开始
…two, one. Now!
他被树叉住了
He's branched off.
没关系 去拿白兰地好吗？
Never mind that. Go and get the brandy, huh?
当然是五星级的汉尼斯
Five-star Hennessy, of course.
殿下
Your Royal Highnesses…
各位来宾
…my lords, ladies and gentlemen…
请向新郎和新娘
…the toast is, the bride and bridegroom:
詹姆斯邦德先生和太太
Mr. and Mrs. James Bond.
- 恭喜你 崔西 - 谢谢
- Good luck, Teresa. - Thank you.
很荣幸能跟
Anyway, it's a pleasure…
让我失去三个 最好的特务的人见面
…to meet the man who cost me three of my best operatives.
对 1964年11月的金块行动
Yes, November '64, the bullion job.
但你的收获也不错 告诉我
You even got away with quite a chunk of the haul. Tell me…
恭喜你 007
Congratulations, 007.
我承认有时候觉得你有点
I must confess that I've sometimes thought you a little…
- 不负责任？- 是的 你说得对
- lrresponsible? - That's exactly the word. Thank you.
- 这次我没什么可以抱怨了 - 我也是
- This time, my boy, I can't complain. - Nor can I.
- 崔西？- 怎么了 爸爸？
- Teresa? - Yes, Papa?
詹姆斯 我们虽没有机会见面
Look, James, I know that we haven't always exactly seen…
别忘了 若有需要
Anyway, don't forget, if there's anything you ever need…
谢谢 这次我有一个小装置 我也懂得用
Thank you. This time I've got the gadgets, and I know how to use them.
记着 听丈夫的话
Remember, obey your husband in all things.
- 答应吗？- 当然了
- You promise me? - But of course I will.
就像我听你的一样
As I always obeyed you.
当然 詹姆斯 祝福你
Of course. Well, James, I wish you luck.
是第一次也是最后一次 记得吗？
For the first and last time. Remember?
她比宝石或黄金更珍贵
An old proverb: "Her price is far above rubies, or even your million pounds."
你是邦德太太了
Just because you are Mrs. Bond…
- 别忘了我的生日 - 我有忘记过吗？
- …don't forget my birthday. - Have I ever?
祝你们幸福
Both of you, maybe all of you.
走吧 詹姆斯
Come on, James.
好开心 亲爱的
Very happy. Be happy, my darling.
走吧
Come on.
进去
On your way.
- 再见 - 小心开车
- Goodbye! - Drive carefully!
钱班霓 没有我你怎么办呢？
Miss Moneypenny, what would you do without me?
我总在婚礼哭泣
I always cry at weddings.
007从不重视政府的财产
007 never had any respect for government property.
我还没给你结婚礼物呢
You know, I haven't given you a wedding present yet.
我有个主意
I had an idea about that.
三个女儿 三个儿子
Three girls, three boys.
- 好吗？- 算是一个好开始
- Pleased? - Not bad for a start.
但我们有一辈子的时间
But, darling, now we have all the time in the world.
拿着花再说一遍吧
Say it with flowers!
我们就好像花店的广告车
He's got a point. We do look like an ad for a flower shop.
我想起了 我从没送花给你过
That reminds me, I didn't even send you flowers.
反正你已经送我结婚礼物了
Anyway, you have given me a wedding present.
是最好的礼物 美好的将来
The best I could have: A future.
邦德太太 住…
Mrs. Bond, shut…
…口 别一次吃光了
…up. And don't eat it all at once.
- 他爱我 - 无法解释的
- He loves me… - Instinctively.
- 无道理的 - 无尽的
- Infuriatingly. - Intensely.
无
In…
- 无 - 无
- In… - In…
无可置疑的
Indubitably.
先生一个男的 再来一个女的
First a boy, and then a girl.
是布费德
It's Blofeld!
It's Blofeld.
没事的
It's all right.
真的 她不过在休息
It's quite all right, really. She's having a rest.
我们很快就走
We'll be going on soon.
别焦急 我们有一辈子的时间
There's no hurry, you see. We have all the time in the world.